Given some sample data how do we populate a ListView?
Let's look at an example of some contact data and how it can be displayed in
the list. We start with our raw data of contacts which is three contacts,
as well as our profile images. Then we pass this data into the adapter so
it has a reference to it. The adapter also knows how to build a list item layout
for each of these data items. So, it could go ahead and create the layouts for
them. But we don't need to create the views yet until the ListView requests that
it needs them. For example, if you had hundreds of contacts here,
you wouldn't want hundreds of layouts sitting around that aren't being used.
Then when you bind the adapter to the ListView,
the ListView will ask how many items are actually in the data set.
And the adapter will check in the data set there's three items, so
we will return that to the ListView. Now the ListView knows that it will have to
populate itself with three list items. Now the ListView starts at position
zero and asks for the list item layout located at that position. It goes back to
the adapter and the adapter checks that at position zero, we have the contact,
Anna. The adapter knows how to create a list item layout from the contact, Anna.
So, it goes ahead and does that. And then we return it to the ListView. And now
we see that the Anna list item is located at the zeroth position in the list.
Next the ListView wants to get the item at position one, so
ask for the layout from the adapter. The adapter checks that at position one,
we have the contact Bob. The adapter knows how to create a list item layout for
Bob so it goes ahead and does that and then it returns it to the ListView. And
now we see that the list item for Bob has been successfully added
to the ListView at position one. Now, the ListView fetches its
last item because it knows that there was three list items to expect.
It fetches the last list item layout at position two by asking the adapter.
The adapter checks that at position two, we have Charlie, as well as that image.
And we know how to make a list item layout for Charlie, so we can go ahead and
do that, and return it to the ListView. And now we have the list item for
Charlie and position two in the list. And we have our complete list